Guide to the Arthur L. Edson papers, 1950-1968 MS2087
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Arthur L. Edson papers
1950-1968
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Edson, Arthur L.
MS2087
9 Linear Feet
Collection consists of teletype printouts, correspondence, note pads, interview transcripts, rough notes, and more. They range in date from 1950 to 1968. They cover US politics, presidential campaign of 1968, the 1964 GOP convention and biographical information and interviews from delegates, candidates, and prominent figures.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition is unknown.
Historical or Biographical Note
Arthur Edson (-1969) brought the Associated Press into the American Newspaper Guild and was a writer for "US News and World Report."
Arthur Edson graduated from the University of Missouri School of Journalism in 1935. His first job was as a sports writer for an Oklahoma paper. He joined the Associated Press (AP) Kansas City Bureau in 1942. He moved to Washington, D.C. in 1945 and was, along with other top AP writers, instrumental in bringing the AP into the American Newspaper Guild. By 1948, he was a top feature writer for AP. He covered presidential politics for twenty-four years and did may feature stories for the AP. He moved to "US News and World Report" in 1968 and was due to take a top position there when his career was cut short by the discovery of cancer.* Arthur Edson died in January 1969.
* Information above supplied by Warner Ragsdale, Jr., a close friend of Edson's. Correction to some dates supplied by Ron Pesch in 2020.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection consists of teletype printouts, correspondence, note pads, interview transcripts, rough notes, and more. They range in date from 1950 to 1968. They cover US politics, presidential campaign of 1968, the 1964 GOP convention and biographical information and interviews from delegates, candidates, and prominent figures. Some of the prominent figures include John F. Kennedy, Robert Kennedy, Charles A. Lindbergh, Eugene McCarthy, John Pastore, Lyndon B. Johnson, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Felix Frankfurter, Barry Goldwater, Carl Hayden, Ezra Taft Benson, Adam Clayton Powell, and Harry S. Truman to name a few.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Political campaigns; Politics and government; Washington (D.C.); Associated Press; Edson, Arthur L.; American Newspaper Guild
- Correspondence, 1950-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "D", 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Acheson, Dean, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Appalachia, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Arkansas, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Benson, Ezra Taft, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Brock, William, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bureaucrats, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bureau of Budget, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Campaign Cost, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Campaign Cost, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Campaign Hoodlumism, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Campaigns (Dangers of), undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- College Students, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Congress - Ain't What it Used to Be, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Congress - Ethics, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Congress - Filibuster - Oratory, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Congress - General, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Congress - Limiting Service Therein, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Congress on TV, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Congress - Senate vs House, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Constitution, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Democrats, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Diplomats, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Dirksen, Everett, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Eisenhower, Dwight D. (See also Ike's Clothes), undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Election Day Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Election Notes, Reforms, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Ex-Presidents, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Ford, Gerald, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Foreign Students, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Frankfurter, Felix, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Goldwater, Barry, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Government (Big), undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Government Information Men, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Hayden, Carl, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Ike's Clothes (Dwight D. Eisenhower), undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Inaugurations, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Inaugurations, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Johnson, Lady Bird, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Johnson, Lyndon Baines, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Kennedy, John F., undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Kennedy, Robert, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Kennedy, Robert, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Knowland, William, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Latimer, Dr. John F., undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Lincoln - Funeral Train Memorial Evaluated, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Lindbergh, Charles A., undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Lobbying, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
- McCarthy, Eugene, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Mail, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Massachusetts (includes material on Edward Brook), undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Mitchell, Howard and Moyers, Bill (see also Presidents and Press), undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
- National Debt, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Negros (Politics), undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Conventions, Politics, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Politics, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Campaign - Spring Interviews, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Election, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Election, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Election - States, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Nixon, Richard, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Ohio (includes material on John Glenn. Robert Taft, Jr.), undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Parliamentarian, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Pastore, John, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Political Name-Calling, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Political Presidential Campaigns, History, and Conventions, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Politicians, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Politics, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Politics (Edson pieces), undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Politics - Elections, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Politics - Value of Name, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Polls, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Poor, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Powell, Adam Clayton, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Presidential Campaigns (includes Whistle-Stopping), undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Presidential Grief, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Presidential Nominations - Rejected, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
- President and Cabinet, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Presidents - Absence from Washington, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Presidents and Gifts, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Presidents and Press, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Presidents and Press, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Presidents and Press (Mostly Moyers), undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
- President's Health, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Presidents - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Presidents - Personal, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
- President's Succession and Running Again, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
- President's Vetoes, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Republican Party, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Rhodes Scholars, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Ribicoff, Abraham, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Scotus and Courts, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Senate, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Star Spangled Banner, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Stassen, Harold, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
- State Department Trip, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Symington, Stuart, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Taxation, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Truman, Harry S., undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
- USIA, undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Udall, Stuart, undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
- Vice Presidency, undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Washington D.C., undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
- Washington D.C., undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Weaver, Robert C., undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Welfare State, undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
- White House, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Writing--especially political, undated (Box 6, Folder 53)